<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Imran Hashmi</title>
    <link>https://imranh27-blog.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Imran Hashmi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 13:14:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://imranh27-blog.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ai Super Powers</title>
      <link>https://imranh27-blog.netlify.app/posts/ai-super-powers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 13:14:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imranh27-blog.netlify.app/posts/ai-super-powers/</guid>
      <description>AI Super-powers China, Silicon Valley and the New World Order. By Kai-Fu Lee I stumbled across Kai-Fu Lee on the on the Lex Fridman AI Podcast, as an aside, this podcast is brilliant and I highly recommend it. The Kai-Fu Lee episode really made me think about societal structure and the role of education. Both the host, Lex Fridman and Kai-Fu both had a deep and humble conversation and they impressed me very much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mind for Numbers</title>
      <link>https://imranh27-blog.netlify.app/posts/mind-for-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 21:07:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imranh27-blog.netlify.app/posts/mind-for-numbers/</guid>
      <description>A Mind for Numbers - How to Excel at Math and Science. By Barbara Oakley I was reading an article on a site where the author was listing their favourite books that made them fall in love with Maths. One of the first books they mentioned was A Mind for Numbers by Barbara Oakley, and this intrigued me. So I have been reading this this past week and, whilst there is precious little Maths in here, but it does detail how to approach learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>https://imranh27-blog.netlify.app/posts/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 20:44:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imranh27-blog.netlify.app/posts/first-post/</guid>
      <description>First post &amp;ldquo;Thinking is nothing but talking to yourself on the inside&amp;rdquo; Richard Feynman.
Hello, so this is a the beginning of my blog and taking that classic quote to heart, I guess this is a way for me to talk to myself a bit clearer and in a bit more organised manner.
The posts will range across a range of topics, from books I am or have read, to software development or just anything that my brain seems to find interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>